Preliminary Inventory to the Eugene Staley Papers, 1923-1988
Hoover Institution Archives
Eugene Staley Papers,
1923-1988
80150
Staley, Eugene, 1906-1989
24 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box (11.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Speeches and writings, correspondence, notes, reports, studies, conference proceedings, curricular material, and printed matter, relating to international economic development assistance to developing countries, education as a means toward economic development, education in internationalism, international relations, international economic relations, and international organization.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1980.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Education; International education; International relations; International organization; Economic assistance; Developing countries; International economic relations; United States--Foreign relations; Economists
Container List
- "'World Studies' Project," 1978 (Box 1.)
- Writings, 1923-1961
- Writings, 1963-1988 (Box 2.)
- Chapters in books
- Articles and speeches, 1932-1940
- Articles and speeches, 1939-1972 (Box 3.)
- Articles and book reviews, 1938-1980 (Box 4.)
- Vita and list of publications
- Fugitive material project, 1936
- Raw materials reports, 1937-1946
- Bureau of the Budget reports, 1942
- United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration (China), 1942-1944 (Box 5.)
- Foreign Service survey, 1945
- United Nations Conference, San Francisco, 1945
- Council on Foreign Relations paper, 1945
- Stanford Business School course, 1945-1946
- Development of International Society Conference, Princeton, 1946
- United Nations Working Group for Asia and the Far East, 1947
- Institute of Pacific Relations (Box 6.)
- World Affairs Council
- Uncompleted projects, 1930-1947
- Cuba mission, 1950
- Communist allegations and security clearance, 1942-1953
- Stanford Research Institute (SRI), 1949-1968
- Venezuela technical institute, 1953
- Manual of Industrial Development, 1955
- SRI small industry research program, 1958-1960 (Box 7.)
- SRI Colombia project, 1962
- SRI Peru project, 1965
- SRI miscellaneous
- Ford Foundation India reports, 1954-1973
- India handloom export reports, 1957-1960
- India small-scale industry reports, 1960-1962
- India reports, 1960-1975 (SRI, Ford Foundation, small industry, occupational training, rural development) (Box 8.)
- India Institute of Rural Management Anand, 1980 (Box 9.)
- India miscellany
- Pakistan small industry report, 1973
- United Nations Conference on the Application of Science and Technology for the Benefit of the Less Developed Areas, 1961
- Nyasaland Economic Symposium, 1962
- Pugwash Conference on Science and World Affairs, Udaipur, India, 1964
- Conference on Development and Cooperation in the South Asia Pacific Region, Kuala Lumpur, Malaya, 1964
- Malaya development materials (Box 10.)
- United Nations Seminar on Industrial Research and Development Institutes in Developing Countries, Beirut, Lebanon, 1964
- Aswan project and Aswan Development Conference, Aswan, Egypt, 1964
- Far East Manpower Assessment and Educational Planning Seminar, Manila, Philippines, 1965
- Society for International Development meeting, Bangkok, Thailand, 1965
- United Nations Centre for Industrial Development, 1965-1967
- Aspen Seminar on Southeast Asia, Aspen, Colorado, 1966 (Box 11.)
- Nigeria occupational training material, 1966
- Kyushu-Yamaguchi International Journalists Seminar, Fukuoka, Japan, 1967
- Conference on the Scientific Revolution, State University of New York, Albany, 1968
- Indonesia education mission, 1970
- United Nations Industrial Development Organization report, 1971
- Asian Development Bank meeting, Manila, Philippines, 1972
- South Pacific Commission Sub-Regional Workshop on Planning Rural Vocational Training, Honiara, Solomon Islands and Rabaul, New Britain, 1975
- Sahel development program, 1977
- Off-Farm Employment Conference, Michigan State University, East Lansing, 1979 (Box 12.)
- Stanford International Development Education Center (SIDEC)
- Economic anthropology course (Education 306A), Stanford University
- Education 306, Stanford University (Box 13.)
- SIDEC miscellany
- Seminar on Economic Problems of Emerging Countries, Stanford University, 1963
- Stanford World Analysis Center, 1974-1976
- Stanford Food Research Institute, 1978-1980 (Box 14.)
- East-West Technology and Development Institute, East-West Center, Honolulu, Hawaii
- Work-oriented general education
- Entrepreneurship
- International Workshop on Entrepreneurial Research and Development, Penang, Malaysia, 1976 (Box 15.)
- East-West Communication Institute, East-West Center, Honolulu, Hawaii
- Hawaii Entrepreneurship Training and Development Institute, Honolulu, 1977-1980
- Endevor-International, 1976-1979
- Entreneurial development and education
- Asia Foundation, 1968 (Box 16.)
- Carnegie Endowment, 1939
- Commission to Study the Organization of Peace, 1939-1981
- Council for the Study of Mankind, 1962-1974 (Box 17.)
- Council on Foreign Relations, 1965-1987
- Ford Foundation, 1962-1963 (Box 18.)
- International Council for Educational Development, 1974
- United Nations Day, 1967
- United Nations revenue, 1961-1969
- United Nations University, 1960-1976
- World Law Fund, 1964
- Alexander, Ramy, correspondence, 1966-1968
- Alexander, Yolanda, correspondence, 1976-1979 (Box 19.)
- Hanna, Paul, correspondence, 1961-1988
- Platt, William, correspondence, 1969-1974
- Stinnes, Edmund H., correspondence, 1961-1977
- Correspondence, 1950
- Correspondence, 1963-1964
- Correspondence, 1965-1967 June (Box 20.)
- Correspondence, 1967 July-1975 (Box 21.)
- Correspondence, 1976-1988 (Box 22.)
- Vietnam mission, 1961
- Vietnam mission, 1961 (Box 23.)
- Development
- Small industry
- Population explosion
- Foreign policy
- Education
- Education (Box 24.)
- Books
- Vietnam mission scrapbook, 196 (Box 25.)